DANIEL GONZÁLEZ-SUÁREZ MARINE BIOLOGIST || COASTAL OCEANOGRAPHER

Linked in ORCID GitHub

Profile

Marine biologist with experience in the technology industry as data analyst. Deeply passionate about studying early development of marine invertebrates. Competent on rearing invertebrates for environmental-stress experiments and knowledgeable in data analysis and visualization with prommaming languages like SQL, R and python.

ACADEMIC DEGREES

2019–2021 MSc in Coastal Oceanography

Universidad Autónoma de Baja California (UABC) Baja California, México

2017-2019 BSc in Marine and Freshwater Resources Management

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica (UNA)

2012–2016 BSc in Marine Biology

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica (UÑA)

Work Experience

Hakkoda 2021-2022

Analytics Engineer I

Worked with database management using SQL, python and R. Developed protocols for exploratory data analysis and designed dashboards for financial services and leading food distributor clients in the US.

INCAPESM, UABC 2021

Research and Training in Production and Growth of Marine Cultures

Worked as laboratory technician, supporting experiments with early development of the Pacific oyster *Crassostrea gigas*. Classified the embroynic and larval stages and assisted in respirometries for larvae. Performed statistical data analysis and created visualizations for final reports of experiments.

EcoDel. IIO 2019–2021

Ecology and Developmental Biology Laboratory, Institute of Oceanologic Research

Laboratory maintenance, experiment execution and report elaboration. Provided experimental design and statistical guidance for postgraduate students.

CIMAR, UCR 2016-2018

Laboratory assistant (Ad honorem)

Assistant to various researchers for projects about echinoderm research, ocean acidification, seagrass ecology, deep-see idenfitication and database management.

RESEARCH

Daniel González-Suárez & José Carlos Hernández (2022). Early developmental stages of the sea urchin Sphaerechinus granularis (Lamarck, 1816) (Echinoidea: Toxopneustidae).
Marine Biology Research, 18:3-4, 266-277, DOI: 10.1080/17451000.2022.2093375

Congresses

V Latin American Echinoderm Congress Virtual	2022
Early developmental stages of the sea urchin Sphaerechinus granularis [Oral Presentation]	
Isla del Coco and Surrounding Waters International Symposium San José, Costa Rica	2018
Marine Biodiversity Database from published records [Poster Presentation]	
III Marine Sciences Scientific Congress Panama City, Panama	2016
Effectivity of Marine Protected Areas in Costa Rica [Oral Presentation]	

Effectivity of Marine Protected Areas in Costa Rica [Oral Presentation]	
Courses & Workshops	
Exploratory Data Analysis in R	2020
Universidad Autónoma de Baja California (UABC) Baja California, México	
Larval Biology of Marine Invertebrates	2019
Friday Harbor Laboratories, University of Washinton Washington, USA	
Effects of dissolved oxygen stress on larval <i>Haminoea vesicula</i> survivorship and growth Selection of vertical zones in low oxygen water columns by larval <i>Dendraster excentricus</i>	
Systematics, Taxonomy and Ecology of Echinoderms	2019
Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) Yucatán, México	
Administration of Marine Biogeographical Data	2018
INVEMAR & OceanTeacher - Global Academy Santa Marta, Colombia	
Python Programming Academic Workshop	2018
Nationa Center for High Technology (CeNAT)	

Nationa Center for High Technology (CeNAT) San José, Costa Rica